In this part, I will share some tips to help you learn, and get the maximum value from this course.
The first tip, make yourself comfortable.
Grab a hot drink, some cake, and a warm blanket if you have to.
Enjoy learning new things, and keep your spirit high.
Thank you for purchasing this course.
Some students that learning online, what they
do is watching the video, and type along to the code or instructions.
This means, when the lesson type a line, the
student also type a line, or pausing the video so often.
So basically, the student type along with the instructor.
My recommendation, is you watch the lecture
for about five to ten minutes, without typing
or if the lecture is quite long like 20 minutes
or more, pause the video for about every ten minutes.
Within that ten minutes period, try to understand:
what are the code or instructions, what are the purpose behind them.
Then you try to replicate them at your environment.
So, instead of just copying the code or instruction,
you get understanding of what is going on and absorb that knowledge.
The next tip is actually about me.
I’m not a native english speaker, so for
some of you, my accent might unusual or even weird.
In such case, I provide the english subtitle
for most of my lectures.
The english subtitle is not an auto generated
one, but I type it manually, so it will be almost 100% accurate.
You can turn on the subtitle from here.
Or maybe I’m speaking too slow, or too fast.
In that case, you can change the playback
speed using this button.
The curriculum is designed to increase step-by-step,
so we start slow at the beginning, but then we run faster.
I recommend that you are not skip any of the
lectures.
If you skip one or more lecture, you might
get lost in later lecture.
However, if there is any optional lecture,
or something that basically a tip, I will make a note on such lecture, so you can skip it without much missing knowledge.
At some point, you might get stuck on a lecture,
and it’s OK.
It’s the joy of learning new things.
We get stuck, we try to find out the solution,
and when we find the solution, we can feel such happy feeling when we overcome challenge.
But, not all of us has enough time to find the solution.
In such case, I recommend few tips:
1st, if it’s about the course content, find
out the Q and A section on the course.
You can find similar issue there, or ask the
question to instructor.
2nd, go to stack overflow.
You know, stack overflow is like a global
knowledge for programming questions.
Or you can always google.
At some time during the course, udemy might
ask you to rate the course.
Please give a rate and review, so I can keep
improve the course, and some other people can also understand the course strength and
weakness before they purchase it.
If software to be installed is newer than
that being used in this course, it should be OK as long as the major version has not
change.
For example, in some of my java courses, I
use Spring boot 2.
When recording the video, I might use spring boot version 2.2 but then spring boot updated to version 2.4
Since the major version still version 2, the course should still relevant.
If you use spring boot 1 or spring boot 3,
the course might still be usable, but need adjustment.
Or its not usable at all, depends on the product.
In some technical course, it is normal if
you find minor difference between source code
or screen design in video, and the resource
provided on lecture.
It might happen because I update the lecture.
In case newer version available which needs
major change, I will do my best to update the course.